A Guide to the Ang Buhay sa Nayon -- Life in the Valley Oral History Project, 2007-2015: SC 0026
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Ang Buhay sa Nayon -- Life in the Valley Oral History Project,
2007-2015
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Moses, Hannah
de Tablan, Luz M.
SC 0026
.64 cubic feet; 2 boxes
6.35 gigabytes; 191 digital files
Ang Buhay sa Nayon - Life in the Valley Oral History Project, 2007-2015, is comprised of video recordings, transcripts, photographs and a scrapbook documenting twenty-three oral history interviews from seventeen Filipino Americans from the Shenandoah Valley region of Virginia.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
The oral history interviews in this collection were recorded in 2014 by Hannah Moses and Luz M. de Tablan. Interviews were donated to JMU Special Collections in the Spring of 2015.
Bio/Historical Note
Ang Buhay sa Nayon - Life in the Valley Oral History Project, 2007-2015 is an oral history project partnership between James Madison University and the Filipino American Community of the Shenandoah Valley of Virginia. This project is also Hannah Moses' thesis project for her Master's in Local, Public, Regional History from JMU. The website for her digital thesis project can be found here: http://sites.jmu.edu/lifeinthevalley/
Moses began recruiting interviewees at the Harrisonburg, Virginia International Festival on September 27, 2014 and the interviews were completed in the Fall of 2014. For this project, fifteen Philippine-born Filipino Americans and two US-born Filipino Americans shared their life stories in a total of twenty-three interviews. Luz M. de Tablan, the founder of the Filipino American Community in the Shenandoah Valley, worked with Moses to interview Filipino individuals for the oral history project.
As of 2015, there are 1,110 Filipino Americans living in the Shenandoah Valley with the majority residing in the northern counties. Those who volunteered for the project live primarily in the southern portion of the Shenandoah Valley. This collection contains the stories of those who came to the United States between 1963 and 2010 and sheds light on the rural immigrant experience. The collection was officially opened to the public at a reception honoring the interviewees on April 25, 2015.
Scope and Content
Ang Buhay sa Nayon - Life in the Valley Oral History Project, 2007-2015, is comprised of video recordings, transcripts, photographs and a scrapbook documenting twenty-three oral history interviews from seventeen Filipino Americans from the Shenandoah Valley region of Virginia. The interviews were conducted during 2014 and edited and transcribed in 2015.
The project employed a life narrative approach where interviewees were asked to tell their life story and were then asked follow-up questions. Transcribing, editing, and reviewing took place in the Spring of 2015.
All interviews were conducted by Hannah Moses, and some interviews also included Luz M. de Tablan as an active interviewer. In some cases, interviewees wanted to conduct a second interview. Please see the transcripts for details about the interviews including length and date of interview as well as information about each interviewee including age, place of birth, and the date each individual arrived in the Shenandoah Valley.
Please note that video recordings and transcripts for each interview are available for use in the JMU Special Collections Reading Room.
Arrangement
Interviews are listed alphabetically by interviewee's last name.
Related Materials
Moses, Hannah. "Ang Buhay Sa Nayon - Life in the Shenandoah Valley" Masters Thesis Project. http://sites.jmu.edu/lifeinthevalley/
Index Terms
Subjects:
Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- History; Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- History -- 20th century; Immigrants -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Filipino Americans -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)
Genre and Form Terms:
Scrapbooks; oral histories (literary works)
- SC0026-1: Elmer Bonga interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 24, 2014
  - Elmer Bonga Transcripts and Supplemental Documents, October 24, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Elmer Bonga Photographs (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- SC0026-2: Lynn Buchanan interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 28, 2014, December 11, 2014
  - Lynn Buchanan Transcripts and Supplemental Documents, October 28, 2014, December 11, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lynn Buchanan Photographs (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- SC0026-3: Tess Cortes interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 22, 2014, December 10, 2014
  - Tess Cortes Lynn Transcripts and Supplemental Documents, October 22, 2014, December 10, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tess Cortes Photographs (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- SC0026-4: Diony de Tablan interviewed by Hannah Moses and Luz de Tablan, October 24, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- SC0026-5: Luz M. de Tablan interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 16, 2014, December 8, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- SC0026-6: Pamela Aquino Flavell interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 27, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- SC0026-7: Manny Jose interviewed by Hannah Moses, November 22, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- SC0026-8: Elery Kadile interviewed by Hannah Moses and Luz de Tablan, November 23, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- SC0026-9: Jinky T. Knox interviewed by Hannah Moses, November 21, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- SC0026-10: Gemma C. Myers interviewed by Hannah Moses, November 21, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SC0026-11: Hannah Myers interviewed by Hannah Moses, November 25, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- SC0026-12: Michelle S. Ott interviewed by Hannah Moses and Luz de Tablan, November 26, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- SC0026-13: Gina Roy interviewed by Hannah Moses and Luz de Tablan, October 26, 2014, November 23, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- SC0026-14: Eva Tran interviewed by Hannah Moses, November 24, 2014
  - Eva Tran Transcripts and Supplemental Documents, November 24, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Eva Tran Photographs (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- SC0026-15: Andrew Zapanta interviewed by Hannah Moses, December 7, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- SC0026-16: Lita Zapanta interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 30, 2014, November 20, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- SC0026-17: Conrad Zapanta interviewed by Hannah Moses, October 30, 2014, November 20, 2014
  - Conrad Zapanta Transcripts and Supplemental Documents, October 30, 2014, November 20, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Conrad Zapanta Video recordings, October 30, 2014, November 20, 2014 (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- Ang Buhay sa Nayon Reception Headshots (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- Pictorial History of the Filino American Community of the Shenandoah Valley Scrapbook, 2007-2015 (Box OV1)
- Ang Buhay sa Nayon Reception Photographs, April 25, 2015 (Digital-materials SC0026-SET-001)
- Ang Buhay sa Nayon Reception Documents, April 25, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 18)